# Sehajpreet Singh

(289)980-4686 | Sehajpreet.singh@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sehajpreetsingh

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Software Developer at Cineplex with 2 years of experience in technologies like C#, React.js and SQL server. Enthusiastic, highly motivated learner and self-starter, eager to meet and solve challenges. An excellent academic record, ability to understand and test software, working knowledge of Azure DevOps, and a strong understanding of core internet technologies.

#### HIGHLIGHT OF QUALIFICATIONS

- Highly adaptable, flexible, positive and resilient
- Excellent ability to develop, test, document, deploy, analyze and maintain secure program code based on client specifications
- Resourceful team player who excels in building trusting relationships both with customers and colleagues
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills able to understand and convey complex product requirements or technical concepts to technical and non-technical audiences
- Effective critical thinker with proven researching skills

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Skills: C# and ASP.NET MVC

**Web Designing and Development** HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL, Knockout.js, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, XML, Material-ui and JSON

**Tools:** Visual studio, Office 365, FileZilla, brackets, visual studio code, VMware, Jupyter Notebook, Notepad ++, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Azure devops

**Quality Assurance Tools**: Postman

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Developer**

Cineplex Entertainment Ltd.

Jan. 2019 - Present

Toronto, ON

- Worked with Theatrical team to create new features like navbar, COVID Popup on the homepage of cineplex and resolved bugs using knowledge of c#, React.JS, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Worked closely with the ticket generation code to create PDF's to send to client on successful transaction.
- Resolved issues related with mobile API's for login and user authorization to help mobile team to run cineplex app effectively
- Demonstrated ability to create API's to fetch movies and theatres in json format from database
- Worked with designers to add the UI/UX for navigation bar on cineplex.com while at the same time handling the responsiveness using JavaScript
- Used Azure DevOps to work with CI/CD Pipelines and added pull requests for any code changes and release them on website on various environments internal and production
- While working in the agile environment created stories to handle agility CRM updates on the website
- Added accessibility support to complete ticket transaction process from seat selection till successful payment transaction
- Utilized Material-ui with React.JS to create a frontend features while handling API calls to display data on the client side
- Added accessibility support on cineplex.com to meet the W3C WAI standards
- Provided daily updates during SCRUM and attended sprint planning meeting to prepare for new tasks

# Sehajpreet Singh

(289)980-4686 | sehajmagan@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sehajpreetsingh

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Research Assistant / Full Stack Developer

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Sheridan College

Brampton, ON

- Designing a configurator for the client to generate Bill of material and Bill of Operation to help engineers add information to ISAH and SAGE
- Prepared use case diagrams, class diagrams, use case narratives, activity diagrams, wireframes and a report to explain the working of project
- Used various technologies like bootstrap, angular.js and mongoDB to create successful configurator

#### Hatch Instructor (On-call)

Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Hatch Canada

Toronto, ON

- Taught elementary school kids how to make simple animations, drawings, and games using Javascript
- Implement unique teaching methods and demonstrations to motivate and inspire student creativity
- Break tasks down into small, manageable steps to keep learning fun and accessible for all students

# **Student Admission Representative**

Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Brampton, ON

- Assisted with the welcome desk to provide visitors information regarding admissions
- Acted as a tour guide for the prospective students and familiarized them with campus
- Entered student information into CRM database to update information about prospective students

### **EDUCATION**

# **Computer Programmer Diploma**

Jan. 2017-Aug. 2018

Sheridan College

Sheridan College

Brampton, ON

Graduated with Honours

# ADDITIONAL COURSES AND QUALIFICATIONS

#### **Career Hacks Workshop**

July- Aug. 2018

Sheridan College

Brampton, ON

- Enhanced career readiness skills and knowledge
- Workshops included: personal strengths, resume writing, interviewing, job searching, professionalism in the workplace

References Available Upon Request